Erryza Nur Alif

Bojonggede, Jawa Barat | Portfolio | LinkedIn | +6289601025693 | erryzanuralif9@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Having around two years of experience in the field of Quality Assurance and knowing such software testing, test scenarios, bug reporting, test reports, postman, swagger, thunder client, and check log defect k8dash gcp, kibana for bug analysis or defect of applications and automation using cypress, selenium, and katalon. I'm looking for Quality Assurance positions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PT. Indivara Group

Jakarta, ID

Quality Assurance

Sept 2023 – Present

- Create test scenarios for the SIT and UAT PERAA website using a Spreadsheet
- Testing function, testing staging for PERAA, and conducting product testing with manual testing and automation using Katalon
- Collaboration with the developer regarding bugs and explaining that the bug occurred
- Make a bug report around 1 to 5 bugs submitted to QA Lead using a Jira

PT. XL Axiata Tbk

Jakarta, ID

Quality Assurance

Jan 2023 – Apr 2023

- Create a 3-day test scenario for 1 Postpaid MyXL mobile project and COMET website using a Spreadsheet
- Testing function, testing integration, testing staging (pre-prod) for XL prepaid, XL postpaid, Axisnet, and COMET products for three months, and conducting product testing once for one day with manual testing and for automation using selenium.
- Defect and bug analysis by checking log chucker MyXL, K8dash gcp, and Kibana.
- Make a bug report around 1 to 5 bugs submitted to QA Lead using a Spreadsheet and the next day will be followed up by the Product Manager

PT. Karya Kaya Bahagia (Harisenin.com)

Jakarta, ID

Quality Assurance Engineer

Nov 2022 - Jan 2022

- Create test plans and scenarios for 1 website project harisenin.com using a Spreadsheet
- Test automation using Cypress for 1 website project harisenin.com for three months
- Testing API in a project using Postman and collaborating with Backend Developers
- Make a bug report submitted to QA Lead using a Spreadsheet and the next day will be followed up by the Product Manager
- Analyze and investigate by performing cross-browser tests, HTML and CSS checks, security testing by checking cookie and cache encryption after the user logs out, pressing the back button to ensure that the browsing session has expired, and advising front-end developers to create unique elements to facilitate QA to create an automation test script

PT. Sagara Asia Teknologi (Sagara Technology)

Jakarta, ID

Quality Assurance Manual

Jun 2022 – *Sep* 2022

- Create a test case for the tekdi premium subs business solution (teknologi.id) website project using a Spreadsheet
- Do a staging test for the tekdi premium subs business solution (teknologi.id) website project using manual testing
- Make a bug report submitted to QA Lead using a Spreadsheet
- Analyze and investigate by performing cross-browser tests, HTML and CSS checks, security testing by checking cookie and cache encryption after the user logs out, pressing the back button to ensure that the browsing session has expire

EDUCATION

Indraprasta PGRI University

Jakarta, ID

Information Technology / S1

Aug 2017 - Aug 2021

• GPA 3.71/4.00

During college, I studied algorithms, programming, software development methods, databases, and computer security that supports QA skills

Final Project: Designing an Android-Based Patient Registration System at Junia Bhakti ClinicCreate an Android-based Patient List Application using the React Native framework and perform manual testing using Blackbox

BOOTCAMP, LICENSE & CERTIFICATION

- E-course POM Selenium Python (for QA) Ide Jongkok
- QA Engineer Automation Eduwork
- The Complete 2022 Software Testing Bootcamp Udemy
- Certificate Of Trainee Program QA Engineer Specialist Sagara Technology

SKILLS, INTERESTS, & LANGUAGES

Technical Skills: Cypress | Selenium | Katalon | Postman | Swagger | Javascript | Java | Phyton | Github | Gitlab | Trello | Jira | ClickUp | Slack | Notion | Qase.io | Figma | Adobe XD | Html | CSS | Tailwind CSS | Bootstrap | MySQL | Firebase | Microsoft Office

Soft Skills: Communication | Time Management | Problem-Solving | Attention to detail

Interests: Quality Assurance, UI/UX Designer

Language: Indonesian (Native), English (Beginner)

PROJECTS

KWA Demo AppsMar 2024 - Mar 2024

Details: Testing Android and then testing on logins using the POM method Tools: Appium Inspector, Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, Appium

Link : https://github.com/Erryza/Appium-POM

Tiket Kereta Tokopedia

Jun 2023 - Jun 2023

Details: Purchase train tickets via Tokopedia using the POM method

Tools: Cypress, Visual Studio Code

Link: https://github.com/Erryza/Tiket-Tokopedia-POM-Cypress

Swag Labs *Jun 2023 - Jun 2023*

Details: Testing websites such as e-commerce and then testing on logins using the POM

method

Tools: Cypress, Visual Studio Code

Link : https://github.com/Erryza/Saucedemo-POM-Cypress

Swag Labs May 2023 - May 2023

Details: Testing websites such as e-commerce then testing login, logout, selecting products,

and checkout using the Fixtures method

Tools: Selenium

Link : https://github.com/Erryza/Selenium-Python-Fixtures

React Gallery Dec 2023 - Dec 2023

Details: Testing websites to share photos like Instagram then login testing, and sharing your

photos using the BDD method

Tools : Cypress

Link : https://github.com/Erryza/BWA-BDD-Cypress

REFERENCE

Name : Fahmi Khoerullatif

Company : Eduwork

Position : Facilitator QA Eduwork Contact : +62 851-5543-6438